<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./service-in.png" type="QuickForm"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
	<name>Container Input (Table)</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Reads the content of a table from an external caller (e.g the Call Workflow (Table Based) node).
     </shortDescription>
 
 	<fullDescription>
 		<intro>
 		
 			This node receives a KNIME table from an external caller (i.e. the <i>Call Workflow (Table Based)</i> node) 
 			and makes it available at the output port. A configured parameter makes the <i>Container Input (Table)</i> 
 			visible from the external caller and enables the external caller to send a KNIME table to the 
 			<i>Container Input (Table)</i> node.<br/>
			<br/>

			If a data table is connected to the optional input, the node will simply forward this table to the output 
			port unless a table is supplied via the REST API, in which case the supplied table will be available at the 
			output port.<br/>
			<br/>
		
			If no input is given, a configured template table is output.
			
 		</intro>
 
         <option name="Parameter name">
             A name for the input parameter(preferably unique). This name is exposed in the REST interface and in the
             <i>Call Workflow (Table Based)</i> node.
         </option>
 
         <option name="Description">
             A description for the input parameter. The description is shown in the API specification of the REST
             interface. 
         </option>
         
         <option name="Template table">
         	A template table can be used to define a table structure which allows the workflow to execute properly. 
         	The main purpose of the template table is to populate the the "example" field of the generated OpenAPI 
         	output parameter specification, which is presented to end users for documentation purposes. It also allows 
         	downstream nodes to be configured when no external input is provided, which is helpful when adjustments to
         	the workflow are needed.
         </option>
         
         <option name="Set input table as template">
         	By clicking this button, the input table, given one is provided, will be set as the new template table.
         </option>
         
         <option name="Use entire input table">
         	When clicked, the entire input table will be set as the template.
         </option>
         
         <option name="Use only first rows">
         	When clicked, only the first n rows are used as the template table. Can be especially useful when the input
         	table serves as an example in the OpenAPI specification and you want to avoid over specifying the example
         	with too many rows. 
         </option>
         
 	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Any input table">
			An optional input that is directly forwarded to the output of the node, unless overwritten by supplying a 
			table via the REST API.
		</inPort>
	
		<outPort index="0" name="The container table">
			The table contained in this container. A configured template table is output if no table has been injected 
			from an external source. 			
		</outPort>
	</ports>

</knimeNode>
